<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Shiv Suthar</title>
    <link>https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Shiv Suthar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project I: Adult Census Income Prediction</title>
      <link>https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>There are different type of people with different race, sex, country, marrital status etc having different workclass and occupation it become necessary to know in which salary class a person falls. The Goal is to predict whether a person has an income of more than 50K a year or not. This is basically a binary classification problem where a person is classified into the &amp;gt;50K group or &amp;lt;=50K group.
I have created a complete blog to solve this machine learning problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project II: Predict The Price Of Books</title>
      <link>https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>There are many among us who prefer to spend more time with books than anything else. Here we explore a big database of books. Books of different genres, from thousands of authors. In this project, we will use the dataset to build a Machine Learning model to predict the price of books based on a given set of features.
Size of training set: 6237 records
Size of test set: 1560 records</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project III: Image classification of Cats and Dogs</title>
      <link>https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shiv-2025.github.io/Shiv_portfolio/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we have written an algorithm to classify whether images contain either a dog or a cat.  This is easy for humans, dogs, and cats. Your computer will find it a bit more difficult. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
